=Rise of Her Lady Physician=
=Episode 25=
=This Is the Cruelest Revenge on Her!=
The Second Prince
is in critical condition.
He is unconscious,
with leg fractures,
multiple wounds,
and internal organ injuries.
Moreover,
he's been poisoned.
Poisoned?
What really happened?
Your Majesty,
the Second Prince heard
that the First Prince came back,
so he invited him to a horse race.
However, the horses suddenly went mad.
After he fell off, he was
trampled by the horse.
Why would the fine
horses suddenly go mad?
Aye.
Son!
My son!
How could this happen?
What happened?
Who harmed you?
Son, son!
You must save him!
Wu Chunlin,
do you have confidence?
Your Majesty,
His Highness is severely injured.
His organs are bleeding,
let alone the deadly poison.
With such severe injuries,
I'm afraid
it's nearly impossible...
Shut up!
No matter how slim the chance,
you must try your best to save him.
Otherwise, I will hold you accountable!
Your Majesty, regarding
His Highness's condition,
I'm afraid only a laparotomy
might be able to save him.
Nonsense!
A laparotomy
is a near-death gamble.
I suggest conservative treatment.
Rong Zelan,
what are you really up to?
Do you want to harm my son?
Your Grace,
I have no grudge against His Highness.
Why would I harm him?
Rong Zelan,
can the method
really save my son?
Your Majesty,
Divine Healer Hua Tuo
was a pioneer in ulcer treatment.
He successfully removed malignant tumors
and sutured the stomach and intestines.
I believe that
with full preparation,
it is worth a try.
Your Majesty.
I once heard military doctors mention
the method of laparotomy.
Many wounded soldiers
survived thanks to this method.
It is not baseless.
We don't have much time.
Please make a decision.
Someone,
summon Elder Zhong.
Your Majesty, my master is aged,
and his hands were once injured.
Now he can no longer
perform ulcer surgery.
Wu Chunlin,
is there anyone who can do this?
Your Majesty,
the border is at war,
and all the ulcer doctors
are in the army.
We're useless!
None of you can do this!
What use do you have?
How could this happen?
(The Second Prince is innocent,)
(but Consort Ning
caused my mother's unjust death.)
(If the prince dies,)
(Consort Ning will be in extreme pain.)
(This is certainly)
(the cruelest revenge on her.)
Zelan, keep in mind that
benevolence of a healer
knows no status.
Even if they're beggars
or prisoners,
they should be treated equally
with the nobles.
Since we've learned medical skills,
we should treat people with benevolence,
regardless of their wealth,
gender,
or age.
All lives
are equal.
We should try our best to save them.
Okay.
Your Majesty,
I can perform ulcer surgery.
Zelan,
how did you learn
such a perilous method?
My Lord,
when I worked in the Ji'an Office,
I learned ulcer treatment
from Elder Zhong.
Rong Zelan,
are you sure
you can save my son?
I'm sure.
But I have to know what poison it is.
I can't carry out a surgery
unless the poison is gone.
If it penetrates the organs,
no one can save him.
It's Soul-breaking Herb.
The poison is Soul-breaking Herb!
How do you know?
Rong Zelan...
Rong Zelan, I beg you to save my son!
I'm begging you! If you can save him,
I'll give you anything you want!
I'm begging you!
Your Grace,
I think you know
what I really want, right?
I know.
I admit it.
Back then, it was me
who schemed to harm your mother
and caused her tragic death.
Rong Zelan,
I'll admit whatever you want me to say!
But please!
Please save my son!
Consort Ning,
I can't believe it!
Your Majesty,
save His Highness first.
His life is the top priority right now.
As for other things,
we'll talk about it later.
Okay.
Minister Wu,
we still need to discuss
the method of detoxification
and laparotomy.
Okay.
Everyone, stay calm.
Prepare the medicine
according to the prescription.
Don't make any mistakes.
Aye.
The decoction must be prepared
before nightfall.
After nightfall,
poor visibility will make
the laparotomy more dangerous.
Aye.
Let's go!
Lord Wu.
Attendant Rong,
His Highness has taken
the antidote.
We're here to assist you.
If you need us for anything,
just give your instructions.
Minister Wu,
when the surgery begins,
I'll first use acupuncture
to relieve his pain.
Please help me monitor his pulse.
Okay.
Physicians, please assist me
in the laparotomy.
You must be very focused
and do as I say.
Aye.
Lord Song,
it's getting late.
The candles are bright,
but I need more sufficient lighting
to see the details clearly.
Leave it to me.
Acupuncture kit.
I'll use the Soul-fixing Needle
to seal his key acupoints
to prevent excessive bleeding.
She used it this way.
I inserted the needles
into the Shenshu Acupoint,
Weizhong Acupoint,
and Zusanli Acupoint.
What technique is this?
Acupuncture
for local anesthesia.
With my Soul-fixing Needle,
it can ensure
that he won't wake up midway
because of pain.
The needle technique is truly profound.
The anesthesia is done.
We shall begin.